Jules Feiffer
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings, ca. 1940-1995, n.d. (Box 22-59)
  - Plays
    - Carnal Knowledge
      - Film production
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1971-1972, 1978
          - Legal documents, 1973-1977
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973-1974
          - Notes, n.d.
        - Photographs and promotional material, 1971
        - Shooting schedule, 1970
      - Playscript
        - Fragments, “True Confessions,” n.d., (3 folders)
        - Full text, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 34)
        - Revisions, n.d.
      - Screenplay
        - First draft, n.d.
        - Subsequent drafts, 1970, (2 folders)
      - Theater productions
        - Kaufman Theater, New York, N.Y., 1990
        - Pasadena Playhouse, Pasadena, Calif., 1988
        - Stages Repertory Theater, Houston, Tex., 1988
    - “Cherry Tree Lane,” musical adaptation of Mary Poppins, with P. L. Travers (Box 35)
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1982-1985
      - Playscript
        - Draft fragments and notes
          - Holograph, n.d.
          - Typescript, n.d.
        - Outlines, 1981, n.d.
    - “Come Back, Go Away, I Love You” See Container 50, “Passionella”
    - “Comedy Zone,” television script, pilot episode, n.d.
    - Crawling Arnold
      - Playscript
        - Drafts
          - Holograph
          - Typescripts
        - Printed text
      - Theater productions, 1961-1965 For additional material see Container 4, Royalty statements
    - “Deep Pockets,” drafts of screenplay
      - Fragments, n.d.
      - Full text, n.d. (Box 36)
      - Revisions, n.d.
    - Elliot Loves
      - Playscript, drafts
        - Fragments, n.d.
        - Full text
          - Early, n.d.
          - Revised, 1987-1988, (2 folders)
        - Revisions, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 37)
      - Theater productions
        - Correspondence, contracts, and miscellany, 1988-1990 Correspondents include Mike Nichols
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1990
        - Photographs and sketches, 1990
        - Playbills and promotional material, 1990
    - The Explainers
      - Playscript, drafts, n.d.
      - Theater productions
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1961, n.d.
        - Playbills and promotional material, 1961, n.d.
    - Feiffer's America (Box 38)
      - Playscript, drafts, by Russell Vandenbroucke, 1988, (2 folders)
        - British production, 1985
        - Northlight Theater, Evanston, Ill.
          - Correspondence and promotional material, 1987-1988
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1988
    - “Feiffer's Corner,” drafts, possibly for television, 1984, n.d.
    - Feiffer's People
      - Playscript, drafts
        - Fragments, n.d.
        - Full text, n.d.
      - Theater productions, 1962-1975, n.d.
    - God Bless
      - Background material, 1967-1969
      - Correspondence, 1968-1970
      - Playscript
        - Character sketches, outlines, and notes, n.d.
        - Drafts (Box 39)
          - Fragments, n.d., (2 folders)
          - Full text, n.d.
          - Half hour version, 1969
          - Revisions, n.d.
        - Printed text from Plays and Players, 1969
      - Theater productions
        - New Theater for Now, Los Angeles, Calif., 1969
        - Royal Shakespeare Company, London, England
          - Correspondence and playbill, 1968
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1968
          - Photographs, 1968
        - Yale School of Drama, New Haven, Conn.
          - Correspondence and playbill, 1968
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1968
    - Grown Ups
      - Playscript, drafts
        - Full text
          - 1978
          - 1981-1985, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 40)
        - Revisions
          - Holograph, n.d.
          - Typescript
            - 1983
            - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 41)
      - Television productions, “Showtime” and “Great Performances,” 1985-1986
      - Theater productions
        - American Repertory Theatre, Cambridge, Mass., 1981
        - Lyceum Theater, New York, N.Y., 1981-1982
        - Mark Taper Forum, Los Angeles, Calif., 1983
        - Miscellaneous, 1982-1986
    - “Harold Swerg,” n.d
    - Harry, the Rat with Women See Container 29
    - “Head for the DMZ: Political Satire Cabaret,” New York, N.Y., 1968 See also Oversize
    - Hold Me!
      - Playscript, n.d.
      - Theater productions (Box 42)
        - Correspondence, contracts, programs, and promotional material, 1977-1980, n.d.
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1977
    - I Want to Go Home
      - Film production
        - Correspondence, contracts, and miscellany, 1987-1991, n.d.
        - Newspaper clippings and promotional material, 1989 See also Oversize
      - Screenplay
        - Correspondence, notes, sketches, and synopsis, n.d. Correspondents include Alain Renais
        - Drafts
          - Fragments, n.d.
          - Full text
            - “Faux Ami,” n.d., (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 43)
            - Final? n.d.
          - Revisions, 1988, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Knock, Knock
      - Book contract, 1985
      - Playscript, drafts
        - “Cohn of Arc”
          - Fragments, n.d.
          - Full text, 1971, n.d., (3 folders)
          - Revisions, n.d. (Box 44)
        - “Knock, Knock,” n.d.
      - Theater productions
        - Correspondence and miscellany, 1976, n.d.
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1976-1978, n.d.
        - Playbills and promotional material, 1976-1978, n.d.
    - “Little Brucie”
      - Screenplay
        - Background material, 1973-1979, n.d.
        - Drafts (Box 45)
          - Full text, n.d., (3 folders)
          - Revisions, n.d.
        - Memoranda and notes, 1981, n.d.
    - Little Murders See also Container 28, “Car Ride”
      - Articles by Feiffer, 1967, n.d.
      - Book publication, 1966, 1989, n.d.
      - Film production
        - Correspondence and contracts, 1968-1970
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1970-1974, 1988, n.d. (Box 46)
        - Production records, 1970, n.d.
      - General correspondence, 1966-1970 Correspondents include Charles Marowitz, Walter Matthau, and Mike Nichols, (2 folders)
      - Playscript
        - Drafts
          - Full text, 1966, n.d., (2 folders)
          - Revisions
            - Holograph, n.d.
            - Typescript, n.d. (Box 47)
          - Royal Shakespeare Company, London, England, n.d.
          - Schubert Theater, New York, N.Y., n.d., (2 folders)
      - Screenplay, draft, n.d.
      - Theater productions
        - Great Britain
          - Correspondence and contracts, 1966-1967
          - Photographs, playbills, and newspaper clippings, 1967, n.d.
        - Greece, 1974 (Box 48)
        - Italy, 1968, 1985-1986
        - Miscellaneous
          - United States, 1966-1977, 1988-1991
          - Other countries, 1967-1969, 1987, n.d.
        - New York, N.Y.
          - Booth Theater and Broadhurst Theatre
            - Correspondence, playbill, and miscellany, 1967
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1967
          - Circle in the Square Theater
            - Correspondence and playbills, 1968-1970 Correspondents include Lillian Hellman and John Herse
            - Financial records, 1969
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1969
          - Second Stage Theater, 1987
        - Northern Europe and Scandinavia, 1968-1972 See also Oversize
    - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
      - Play notes and ideas, ca. 1950s-ca. 1980s See also Oversize
      - Television situation comedy ideas, ca. 1980s
      - Theater productions based on Feiffer's work, 1962-1966, 1974-1975, 1987
    - “The Needler,” playscript, draft fragments, n.d.
    - “Nevins,” playscript or screenplay ideas
      - Dialogue drafts, n.d.
      - Notes, n.d.
    - “Nuclear Follies,” television script and correspondence, 1984-1985, n.d.
    - “N.V.,” filmscript
      - Full text, 1989, (2 folders)
      - Revisions, n.d.
    - “The Page Boys,” television script, pilot episode, 1990-1991, (7 folders) (Box 50)
    - “Passionella” or “Come Back, Go Away, I Love You”
      - Correspondence and contracts, 1960-1967
      - Musical lyrics by Stephen Sondheim, n.d.
      - Playscript, drafts, 1959-1963, (2 folders)
    - “Play for Two Characters,” playscript, draft, n.d.
    - Popeye
      - Essay, “Popeye Introduction,” 1984
      - Film production
        - Correspondence, contract, essay by Marie Segar Clausen, and promotional material, 1977-1980
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1980, n.d.
        - Shooting schedule, 1980 (Box 51)
      - Screenplay
        - Drafts
          - Fragments
            - Holograph, n.d.
            - Typescript, n.d.
          - Full text, 1979, n.d., (4 folders)
        - Film treatment, 1978, n.d.
    - Puss in Boots
      - Screenplay, n.d.
      - Television production, 1984 (Box 52)
    - “The Satan Prize”
      - Correspondence and background material, 1992, n.d.
      - Script for television, drafts
        - Fragments
          - Holograph, n.d.
          - Typescript, n.d.
        - Full text, 1992
    - Sessions, “Gunfight at the Bookman Corral” episode for Billy Crystal
      - Correspondence and transcript of conversation, 1991
      - Script, drafts
        - Fragments, n.d.
        - Full text, 1991
    - “So True,” screenplay
      - Correspondence and storyline transcript, 1992
      - Drafts
        - Fragments
          - Holograph, n.d.
          - Typescript, 1993, n.d.
        - Full text, 1993
    - “Street Song,” playscript, act one, by Calvin Trillin and Jules Feiffer (Box 53)
      - Full text
        - “The Steinettes Musical,” draft, n.d.
        - “Streetsong,” draft with article about the Steinettes by Trillin, 1979
      - Notes, n.d.
      - Revisions, n.d.
    - A Think Piece
      - Playscript
        - Drafts
          - Fragment, n.d.
          - Full text, 1978-1979, n.d., (5 folders)
          - Revisions
            - Holograph and typescript, n.d.
            - Typescript, n.d. (Box 54)
        - Reading scripts
          - Circle Repertory Company, preproduction script, n.d.
          - Manhattan Theater Club, New York, N.Y., 1979, n.d.
      - Theater production
        - Correspondence and contract, 1982, n.d.
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1982, n.d.
        - Playbills and production and promotional material, 1982-1986, n.d.
    - White House Murder Case
      - Playscript, drafts
        - Fragments, n.d.
        - Full text, 1969, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Revisions, n.d. (Box 55)
      - Theater productions
        - Correspondence and contract, 1970, n.d.
        - Financial records, 1970
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1970-1976, n.d.
        - Playbills and photograph, and promotional material, 1970-1976, n.d.
    - Untitled juggler skit, n.d.
  - Speeches
    - 1959-1965, miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - 1965, “The Role of the Social Critic,” Center Club luncheon, New York, N.Y.; University of Massachusetts, Amherst, Mass., Distinguished Visitors Program
    - 1966-1971, miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - 1972, speeches concerning the Vietnamese conflict and George S. McGovern's presidential election campaign
    - 1974, “Speech at Yale Political Union,” Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
    - 1977, “How Not to Talk to Each Other” (Box 56)
    - 1978-1981, miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - 1981, “Movie-America,” Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, N.Y.
    - 1982-1985, miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - 1986-1987, miscellaneous (Box 57)
    - 1987, “The Superhero in America,” Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.
    - 1988-1994, miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - 1995, miscellaneous (Box 58)
    - Undated
      - Introductions and memorial tributes
      - Notes and fragments, (2 folders)
  - Stories and notes for stories, ca. 1940s-ca. 1950s ٌSee also Oversize, (2 folders) (Box 59)
- Oversize, 1958-1989, n.d. (Box OV 1-OV 3)
  Calendars, correspondence, invitations, advertisements, posters, and writings.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Family and Biographical File (Box OV 1)
    - Appointment calendars, 1967 (Container 1)
    - Family correspondence
      - Other family members, n.d. (Container 3)
  - General Correspondence
    - Chronological file
      - 1979 (Container 14)
      - 1989 (Container 15)
    - Subject file
    - Crile, Susan, n.d. (Container 17)
  - Art Publication File (Box OV 2)
    - Advertisements, 1959 (Container 19)
    - Books
      - Explainers, poster, n.d. (Container 19)
      - Passionella, poster, 1960 (Container 20)
      - Sick, Sick, Sick, poster, n.d. (Container 20)
    - Calendars, 1966 (Container 21)
    - Cards, announcements, and invitations, 1960 (Container 21)
    - Cartoons and comic strips
      - Notes and promotional material, posters, n.d. (Container 22)
  - Writings (Box OV 3)
    - Plays
      - “Head for the DMZ: Political Satire Cabaret,” New York, N.Y., poster, 1968 (Container 41)
      - I Want to Go Home
        - Film production
          - Newspaper clippings and promotional material, poster, 1989 (Container 42)
      - Little Murders
        - Theater productions
          - Northern Europe and Scandinavia, poster, Teatr Polski, 1969 (Container 48)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Play notes and ideas
          - “The Boy Who Was a Window Shade,” ca. 1950s (Container 49)
          - “Red, White, and Walter Birdwell,” ca. 1950s (Container 49)
        - Writings
          - Stories and notes for stories, ca. 1940s-ca. 1950s (Container 58)